Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Feminism & Women's Movements TAM.566
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Feminism & Women's Movements
2009-
TAM.566
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites: i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Feminism & Women's Movements, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library, which was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program (Library of Congress) and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. The collection contains periodically archived web sites of feminist, women's movements and women's rights entities that reflect a left/progressive viewpoint. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Content Note
Contains periodiclaly archived websites of left feminist and/or women's movements entities, with a special emphasis on New York City based activity. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Feminism & Women's Movements, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program (Library of Congress) and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the web page Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Feminism |z United States.; Feminism.; Feminist theory.; Feminists |z United States.; Reproductive rights |z United States.; Socialist feminism |z United States.; Women's rights |z United States.
- CODEPINK: Women for Peace, 11/9/2009 -
- Gray Panthers, 11/16/2009 -
- NYFAI: New York Feminist Art Institute, 1/13/2010 -
- Redstockings: Women's Liberation Studies Archives for Action, 11/9/2009 -
- SisterSong, 5/12/2011-
- The Sex Workers Project, 5/3/2011-
- Veteran Feminists of America, 11/9/2009 -
- Women's Fightback Network, 5/2/2011-
- Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF), 8/13/2009 -
- Worldwide Vigils: Women in Black, 7/23/2010 -